<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Sid&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.thefossrant.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Sid&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.thefossrant.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Badly written analytics script causes cascading homelab failure</title>
      <link>https://blog.thefossrant.com/posts/9.-badly-written-analytics-script-causes-cascading-homelab-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.thefossrant.com/posts/9.-badly-written-analytics-script-causes-cascading-homelab-failure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This all started a couple weeks ago. Things started to slow down on my homelab server. My Minecraft server kept crashing. I thought that the Minecraft server was the cause of this because it has a lot of memory allocated to it and every time this would happen, the memory would fill up and the Minecraft server would crash. That thought was further reinforced when I noticed the memory was almost about to overflow when I stopped my Minecraft server and the memory usage significantly went down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roast your developer portfolio</title>
      <link>https://blog.thefossrant.com/posts/7.-roast-your-developer-portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.thefossrant.com/posts/7.-roast-your-developer-portfolio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have just made yet another website! This one is inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github-roast.pages.dev/&#34;&gt;codenoid/github-roast&lt;/a&gt;. Basically you just input a link to your portfolio site and it roasts it. Once you roast it, make sure to post it to Mastodon and Twitter with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.social/tags/devportfolioroast&#34;&gt;#devportfolioroast&lt;/a&gt; hashtag.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The front-end was written in HTML, CSS, and JS and the backend fully in Python. Once you input the URL, the backend will send a request to the Gemma:2B model from Google using Ollama. It will then send the roast back to the browser and display it. The site is super simple.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now it is time for you to go and roast your portfolio: &lt;a href=&#34;https://portfolio-roast.thefossrant.com/&#34;&gt;https://portfolio-roast.thefossrant.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
